First it takes hold of your mind...then it takes hold of your life.
The Number 23 is a thriller, mystery, crime film directed by Joel Schumacher.
Animal control officer Walter Sparrow becomes obsessed with a novel that he believes was written about
him, as more and more similarities between himself and his literary alter ego seem to arise.
Walter Sparrow / Fingerling, played by Jim Carrey.
Agatha Sparrow / Fabrizia, played by Virginia Madsen.
Robin Sparrow, played by Logan Lerman.
Isaac French / Dr. Miles Phoenix, played by Danny Huston.
Suicide Blonde / Mrs. Dobkins / Young Fingerling's
Mother, played by Lynn Collins.
Laura Tollins, played by Rhona Mitra.
The Number 23 is a 2007 American psychological thriller film written
by Fernley Phillips and directed by Joel Schumacher.
Jim Carrey stars as a man who becomes obsessed with the 23 enigma once he reads
about it in a strange book that seemingly mirrors his own life.
The film was released in the United States on
February 23, 2007 by New Line Cinema.
This is the second film to pair Schumacher and
Carrey, the first being Batman Forever.
The film was a financial success, grossing $77.6 million against a $30 million
budget, but received generally negative reviews from critics.
Despite this, Carrey was proud of the film, saying: "I was able to explore the darker edges
of my personality, which really was a blast and something different for me."
The film explores themes of hotel room, suicide, based on
novel or book, obsession, sadomasochism.
The tone is intense and mind_bending.